The magic's back, warts and all.
Nanny McPhee and the Big Bang is a comedy, fantasy,
family film directed by Susanna White.
Nanny McPhee appears at the door of a harried young mother who is trying
to run the family farm while her husband is away at war.
But once she’s arrived, Nanny discovers that the children are fighting a war of
their own against two spoiled city cousins who have just moved in.
Relying on everything from a flying motorcycle and a statue that comes to life to a tree-climbing piglet
and a baby elephant, Nanny uses her magic to teach her mischievous charges five new lessons.
Nanny McPhee, played by Emma Thompson.
Norman Green, played by Asa Butterfield.
Megsie Green, played by Lil Woods.
Vincent Green, played by Oscar Steer.
Celia Gray, played by Rosie Taylor-Ritson.
Cyril Gray, played by Eros Vlahos.
Nanny McPhee and the Big Bang (released in the United States and Canada as Nanny McPhee Returns) is a 2010 period fantasy comedy film directed by Susanna White, produced by Tim
Bevan, Eric Fellner and Lindsay Doran with music by James Newton Howard and co-produced by StudioCanal, Relativity Media, Working Title Films and Three Strange Angels.
It is a sequel to the 2005 film Nanny McPhee.
It was written by Emma Thompson, based on
Christianna Brand's Nurse Matilda books.
Thompson reprises her role as Nanny McPhee, and it also stars Maggie Gyllenhaal, Ralph
Fiennes, Rhys Ifans, Ewan McGregor, Asa Butterfield and Maggie Smith.
It was theatrically released on 2 April 2010 in Europe by Universal Pictures.
It received positive reviews from critics and it earned
$93.2 million on a $35 million budget.
It also received a Young Artist Award nomination for
Best Performance in a Feature Film.
The film was released on DVD and Blu-ray in the UK on 19 June 2010.
The film explores themes of nanny, nostalgic,
aftercreditsstinger, duringcreditsstinger, woman director.
The tone is lighthearted.